

Software engineer **Designer Entrepreneur**

Anders Borch

Frederiksborggade 15, 3rd, 1360 Copenhagen, Denmark

+45 50182053

anders@borch-andersen.com



https://cyborch.com



https://borch-andersen.com

Noteworthy Work Experience



Jun 2017 - Jun 2018 СТО



Sep 2008 - Jul 2010 iOS Software Manager



Jun 2018 - Dec 2020 Senior Software Engineer

My role was leading a small team of 3 developers, developing the iOS BLE stack, and a backend service, as well as defining the product and managing external contractors handling Android BLE stack and hardware development. I was head of the iOS application development department in the largest phone company in the world. Here I managed a team working on developing iOS software for Vodafones new social services.

My role is that of researching, prototyping, and demonstrating uses for emerging technologies, especially with a focus on IoT and blockchain.

See full description below.

Skills

Agile

Management

Yoga

MariaDB

Postgres

Mongo

Kotlin

Swift

Javascript



Hobbies & Interests











Puppies

About Me

I am a software engineer, a designer and an entrepreneur. I have worked in software engineering in 20 years and have over 7 years of management experience. I moved from Denmark to America 7 years ago, lived in Spain for a short while and moved back to Denmark few years ago.

Proven Experience

- Over 7 years of management experience
- Introducing Agile methodologies in startup teams
- Software engineering at all levels from hardware, to server side, to iOS

Achievements

- Team leader for iOS development department in worlds largest phone company
- Product in Top 3 Best App of the Year in New York Times
- Worked with multiple successful Silicon Valley startups

Programming Languages

In no particular order: C, C++, Pascal, x86 Assembler, ARM Assembler, Java, Perl, PHP, Python, Postscript, Swift, Objective-C, Javascript, Typescript, Ruby, Kotlin probably more that I have forgotten about.

Education

Scrum Master certification, Xebia - 2009
Project management course, Magisterunion - 2006
Computer science, CBS - 1996 - 1998
Bagsværd private school - 1989 - 1996
Gladsaxe primary school - 1984 - 1989

Full Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer

III Jul '18 - Dec '20



Tradeshift is a platform provider for B2B document transfer. It has gone through several rounds of funding with the latest round of \$250m. Tradeshift Frontiers is the emerging technology department, which does R&D in all things that has to do with IoT, blockchain, and Al. My role is that of researching, prototyping, and demonstrating uses for emerging technologies, especially with a focus on IoT and blockchain.

Lead iOS Engineer, KlikKit

🎏 Jun '17 - Jun '18



At KlikKit, we were building a product which helps people make good habits stick. I joined a small team of developers working on building an app which connects to a physicals button to track retention and compliance on anything from a daily run to remembering to take your daily prescription medicine. My role is leading a small team of 3 developers, developing the iOS BLE stack, and a backend service, as well as defining the product and managing external contractors handling Android BLE stack and hardware development. Ultimately the team wasn't able to find funding and we had to move on.

Work Experience, continued

Scrum Master, Shootr

Jun '16 - May '17



Shootr is building an application that solves the issue of people switching their attention to the "second screen" - the mobile phone - when there is a commercial break in the TV show they are watching. I worked as a Scrum Master to improve both the application quality and the team process. Sadly my tenure there was cut short by personal life events that forced me to move back to Denmark.

iOS Software Director, Athos

Jun '14 - May '16



At Athos I worked as a a iOS engineering director. As the director I have rebuilt the user experience and the engineering process from an internal prototype built by interns into a mature and well architected product built by a team of engineers using proper QA and project management procedures.

iOS Software Lead, Lumo Body Tech

Mov '11 - May '14



I worked at Lumo Body Tech as a the iOS software lead and was responsible for building their Lumo Lift app which is still their flagship product.

Senior Software Engineer, Epic Think Media

Marg 10 - Oct 11



My first assignment was creating a movie review app for PluggedIn (www.pluggedin.com). It was described by company management as "more pixel perfect than any of our previous apps" and "a benchmark for future Brushfire apps." My next assignment was the "Tiger Woods: My Swing" golf swing analyzer app which was named top 3 Best App of the Year in New York Times.

iOS Software Manager, Vodafone

🎏 📁 Sep '08 - Jul '10



With Vodafone I was head of the iOS application development department. I started out in ZYB before it was acquired by Vodafone. While in ZYB I made the first version of the social networking and synchronization application. After Vodafone acquired ZYB, I became software manager for a team of 5 developers and 2 testers working on developing iOS software for Vodafones new social services.

Senior Software Engineer, Zmags

EDec '06 - Aug '08



Zmags builds software which can convert PDF files into flash based online publications. One month before I started in Zmags their only full time developer had stopped. I ensured that proper development, test, and release procedures were established for the development department which employed 10 developers by the time I left.

Software Developer, NeoConsult

Sep '05 - Nov '06



NeoConsult builds software for telecom companies. With NeoConsult I was responsible for implementing their new generation of phone number portability systems and have been involved in development and maintenance of provisioning and invoicing systems for customers in several countries.

Earlier Work Experience

My earlier work experience includes ComX Networks (2002 - 2005) and Netropolis (1998 - 2002). Please feel free to ask if you want to know more about my earlier work experience.